

# **JOSEPH RALAIZANAKA**

# **Data Scientist / Python Developer**

# **ABOUT ME**

After more than fifteen years in the financial markets, I decided to start a career change in the field of data science. Indeed, passionate about the world of data and noticing that there is a synergy between these two worlds, I acquired a perfect knowledge of the design and development in data sciences allowing me to bring value to the data of a company.

#### CONTACT

- j.ralaizanaka@gmail.com
- (33) 6.10.47.38.65
- 4 rue des Yvelines, 91130 Ris-Orangis
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-ralaizanaka/
- https://bilandecompetencev1.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/jralaizanaka/Data-Science-Projects-Porfolio

## **DATA SKILLS**

- · Building and feeding a data management infrastructure
- · Exploratory, descriptive and inferential analysis of data
- Predictive analysis of structured and unstructured data by artificial intelligence
- Industrialization of a machine learning algorithm and automation of decision-making processes
- · Management of data management projects
- Application development in Python

## DATA SCIENCE TECHNOLOGY

 $\textbf{Programming Language:} \ \textbf{Python} \ \textbf{,} \ \textbf{SQL} \ \textbf{,} \ \textbf{Scala} \ \textbf{,} \ \textbf{VBA}$ 

Data Base: SOL

Dataviz: Matplolib, Seaborn, Plotly, Bokeh

**Machine Learning / Deep Learning:** 

Classification, Régréssion, Clustering, Textmining, ScikitLearn,

Tensorfow, Keras

Big Data: Spark, AWS

Softwares: Git, GitHub, Streamlit, Xlwings, Python-Docx,

Power Bi

#### **OTHER SKILLS**

Alternative portfolio management

Stock market tools: Bloomberg, Reuters, Waldata

Office Pack: Excel, Word, PPT

### **LANGUAGES**

French, Malagasy: native language

English : C1

# CENTRE D'INTERET

Reading, Salsa, Running

# EXPÉRIENCE |

#### Data Scientist/Python Developper

Sas Bien Commun - Paris | since january 2022

- Automation of invoicing process
- Implementation of profitability analysis dashboard
- Design, deployment and maintenance of a multilingual skills assessment web application (streamlit and heroku technology)
- Development of Web Analytics applications (automation of tagging plan and SEO)

#### **Entrepreneurial project**

Creation of a data strategy firm | 2020-2002

- Creation of an algorithm evaluating the state of "zombification" of a company from its financial reports
- Development of a POC
- · Establishment of the business model and business plan
- Creation of a pitch deck
- · Search for investors

#### **Business Data Analyst**

Développement Finance Innovation -Paris | 2013-2019

- Implementation of a python solution for high frequency data management:
- Ingestion, transformation, cleaning of raw data
- Data analysis
- Data processing for use in stock market strategies based on fractals and chaos theory

#### Trader

Arborescence Capital - Paris | 2007-2012

- Implementation of LONG/SHORT TRADE from a trading model based on fractals
- Placing orders on CFDs
- Monitoring of companies listed on the main European markets

#### **Alternative Research Analyst**

CM-CIC Securities-Paris | 2002-2006

- · Development of alternative investment strategies
- · Creation of option book monitoring dashboards
- Implementation of "Bact Testing" modules
- Technical analysis and management of derivative positions

#### **EDUCATION**

## Fullstack Data Science registered at RNCP 35288

Jedha | 2020

- 420 hours of training in Data Science
- Machine Learning pipeline design and prototyping to bring value to business data
- Modeling of data analysis results to make them readable, exploitable and actionable
- Certificate "Designer Developer in Data Science"

# 3rd specialized cycle Trading, Finance et Négoce International

ESLSCA Business School Paris | 2002

• In-depth training in expertise techniques in the field of Financee

## Master's degree in Applied Economics Finance sector

Université Paris Dauphine PSL | 2000

• Training in quantitative techniques, statistical and IT tools used in economics professions